{"data":{"postgres":{"establishment":[{"establishmentid":"5171","name":"La Noria Bistro","address":"5517 Michigan Ave","zipcode":"48213","owner":"Norberto Garita","licenseNumber":"229238","licenseType":"Fixed Establishment","mostRecentLicenseDate":"4/30/2018","establishmentType":"Food Service Establishment","establishmentStatus":"Open","riskCategory":"High","reviewFrequencyDays":"180.0","geom":"0101000020E61000008C9264111BC754C01051715B5C2A4540","inspectionsByEstablishmentidList":[{"inspectionid":"43842","establishmentid":"5171","name":"La Noria Bistro","inspectionDate":"2018-10-03T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"128","pcount":"1","pfcount":"0","ccount":"1","criticalcount":"1","noncritical":"1","correctedcritical":"1","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"43842","inspectionDate":"10/3/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"5171","name":"La Noria Bistro","violationCode":"3-501.13","violationDescription":"POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  shall be thawed:  Under refrigeration, or under cool running water (<70° F), or as part of cooking process, and total accumulated time above 41° F, for thawed portions, shall not exceed 4 hours.  Any thawing procedure may be used for immediate service for individual consumers order of READY-TO-EAT foods.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Frozen food(s) for thawing","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F thawed or partially thawed","subProblem":"At room temperature","location":"COUNTER","subLocation":"KITCHEN","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2018-10-03T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store under refrigeration."},{"inspectionid":"43842","inspectionDate":"10/3/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"5171","name":"La Noria Bistro","violationCode":"3-302.11","violationDescription":"(A) FOOD shall be protected from cross contamination by:  \r\n(1) Except as specified in (1)(c) below, separating raw animal FOODS during         storage, preparation, holding, and display from:\r\n(a) Raw READY-TO-EAT FOOD including other raw animal FOOD such as FISH for sushi or MOLLUSCAN SHELLFISH, or other raw READY-TO-EAT FOOD such as fruits and vegetables,(P) and\r\n(b) Cooked READY-TO-EAT FOOD; (P)\r\n(c) Frozen, commercially processed and packaged raw animal FOOD may be          stored or displayed with or above frozen, commercially processed and           packaged, ready-to-eat food.\r\n(2) Except when combined as ingredients, separating types of raw animal FOODS    from each other such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, and POULTRY during storage,        preparation, holding, and display by:\r\n(a) Using separate EQUIPMENT for each type, (P) or\r\n(b) Arranging each type of FOOD in EQUIPMENT so that cross contamination of one type with another is prevented, (P) and\r\n(c) Preparing each type of FOOD at different times or in separate areas; (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Raw animal food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored over/next to","subProblem":"","location":"COOK LINE AREA","subLocation":"Above the ACCESS","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-10-03T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store raw animal foods below and away from foods needing little or no further prep."}]},{"inspectionid":"41805","establishmentid":"5171","name":"La Noria Bistro","inspectionDate":"2018-03-20T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"128","pcount":"1","pfcount":"2","ccount":"0","criticalcount":"3","noncritical":"0","correctedcritical":"3","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"41805","inspectionDate":"3/20/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"5171","name":"La Noria Bistro","violationCode":"3-501.17","violationDescription":"(A)  READY-TO-EAT, POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  prepared and held refrigerated for more than 24 hours in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT  shall be clearly marked at the time of preparation to indicate the date or day by which the FOOD shall be consumed. (Pf)\r\n(B)  A container of refrigerated, commercially prepared READY-TO-EAT POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  shall be clearly marked, at the time the original container is opened in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT, to indicate the date or day by which the FOOD shall be consumed. (Pf)\r\n\r\nA date marking system that does not exceed 7 days, including date of preparation, or opening is to be used. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"In house prepared ready-to-eat potentially hazardous  food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Without date of consumption marking","subProblem":"","location":"COOLERS THROUGHOUT","subLocation":"Above the ACCESS","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-03-20T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Datemark with a discard date of 7 days or less."},{"inspectionid":"41805","inspectionDate":"3/20/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"5171","name":"La Noria Bistro","violationCode":"3-302.11","violationDescription":"(A) FOOD shall be protected from cross contamination by:  \r\n(1) Except as specified in (1)(c) below, separating raw animal FOODS during         storage, preparation, holding, and display from:\r\n(a) Raw READY-TO-EAT FOOD including other raw animal FOOD such as FISH for sushi or MOLLUSCAN SHELLFISH, or other raw READY-TO-EAT FOOD such as fruits and vegetables,(P) and\r\n(b) Cooked READY-TO-EAT FOOD; (P)\r\n(c) Frozen, commercially processed and packaged raw animal FOOD may be          stored or displayed with or above frozen, commercially processed and           packaged, ready-to-eat food.\r\n(2) Except when combined as ingredients, separating types of raw animal FOODS    from each other such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, and POULTRY during storage,        preparation, holding, and display by:\r\n(a) Using separate EQUIPMENT for each type, (P) or\r\n(b) Arranging each type of FOOD in EQUIPMENT so that cross contamination of one type with another is prevented, (P) and\r\n(c) Preparing each type of FOOD at different times or in separate areas; (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Raw animal food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored over/next to","subProblem":"","location":"COOK LINE AREA","subLocation":"Above the ACCESS","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-03-20T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store raw animal foods below and away from foods needing little or no further prep."},{"inspectionid":"41805","inspectionDate":"3/20/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"5171","name":"La Noria Bistro","violationCode":"4-302.12","violationDescription":"(A) FOOD TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICES shall be provided and readily accessible for use in ensuring attainment and maintenance of FOOD temperatures as specified under Chapter 3. (Pf)   \r\n(B) A TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICE with a suitable small-diameter probe that is designed to measure the temperature of thin masses shall be provided and readily accessible to accurately measure the temperature in thin FOODS such as MEAT patties and FISH filets. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Food thermometer(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"RESTAURANT","subLocation":"Above the ACCESS","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-03-20T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide."}]},{"inspectionid":"41467","establishmentid":"5171","name":"La Noria Bistro","inspectionDate":"2018-02-12T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Plan Review/Final/Ap","inspectorid":"129","pcount":"0","pfcount":"0","ccount":"1","criticalcount":"0","noncritical":"1","correctedcritical":"0","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"41467","inspectionDate":"2/12/2018","inspectionType":"Plan Review/Final/Ap","establishmentid":"5171","name":"La Noria Bistro","violationCode":"6-202.15","violationDescription":"Outer openings of a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT shall be protected against the entry of insects and rodents. Unless otherwise allowed by law. \r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Outer opening(s)","subItem":"door(s)","problemDescription":"Not provided with","subProblem":"Screening that is sixteen mesh to the inch or greater","location":"OUTER DOOR(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Repair/replace to meet requirements above."}]},{"inspectionid":"41374","establishmentid":"5171","name":"La Noria Bistro","inspectionDate":"2018-02-02T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Plan Review/Pre-Open","inspectorid":"129","pcount":"1","pfcount":"1","ccount":"9","criticalcount":"2","noncritical":"9","correctedcritical":"0","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"41374","inspectionDate":"2/2/2018","inspectionType":"Plan Review/Pre-Open","establishmentid":"5171","name":"La Noria Bistro","violationCode":"6-201.13","violationDescription":"(A) In FOOD ESTABLISHMENTS in which cleaning methods other than water flushing are used for cleaning floors, the floor and wall junctures shall be coved and closed to no larger than one thirty-second inch.\r\n(B) The floors in FOOD ESTABLISHMENTS in which water flush cleaning methods are used shall be provided with drains and be graded to drain, and the floor and wall junctures shall be coved and SEALED.","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Floor(s)","subItem":"juncture not attached at wall","problemDescription":"Not coved","subProblem":"","location":"WALL(S)","subLocation":"At the Coved molding","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide / install coved molding."},{"inspectionid":"41374","inspectionDate":"2/2/2018","inspectionType":"Plan Review/Pre-Open","establishmentid":"5171","name":"La Noria Bistro","violationCode":"6-303.11","violationDescription":"Light of the proper intensity shall be provided as specified.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Lighting intensity","subItem":"at 30 inches above the floor","problemDescription":"Less than","subProblem":"10 foot candles","location":"WALK-IN COOLER","subLocation":"At the Lights","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide as required"},{"inspectionid":"41374","inspectionDate":"2/2/2018","inspectionType":"Plan Review/Pre-Open","establishmentid":"5171","name":"La Noria Bistro","violationCode":"3-305.11","violationDescription":"FOOD shall be protected from contamination by storing the FOOD:\r\n(1)     In a clean, dry location;\r\n(2)     Where it is not exposed to splash, dust, or other contamination; and\r\n(3)     At least 15 cm (6 inches) above the floor, unless otherwise approved.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Food item(s) in storage","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Exposed to dust, splash, or other contaminates","subProblem":"","location":"BAR","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Store in manner that does not contaminate items"},{"inspectionid":"41374","inspectionDate":"2/2/2018","inspectionType":"Plan Review/Pre-Open","establishmentid":"5171","name":"La Noria Bistro","violationCode":"4-402.11","violationDescription":"EQUIPMENT that is fixed because it is not EASILY MOVABLE shall be installed so that it is spaced to allow access for cleaning along the sides, behind, and above the EQUIPMENT or sealed as required,  COUNTER-MOUNTED EQUIPMENT that is not EASILY MOVABLE shall be installed to allow cleaning of the EQUIPMENT and areas underneath and around the EQUIPMENT .\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Fixed equipment","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not sealed to adjoining","subProblem":"Wall(s)","location":"EQUIPMENT","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Seal to wall/equipment to facilitate cleaning."},{"inspectionid":"41374","inspectionDate":"2/2/2018","inspectionType":"Plan Review/Pre-Open","establishmentid":"5171","name":"La Noria Bistro","violationCode":"6-202.15","violationDescription":"Outer openings of a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT shall be protected against the entry of insects and rodents. Unless otherwise allowed by law. \r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Outer opening(s)","subItem":"door(s)","problemDescription":"Not provided with","subProblem":"Screening that is sixteen mesh to the inch or greater","location":"OUTER DOOR(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Repair/replace to meet requirements above."},{"inspectionid":"41374","inspectionDate":"2/2/2018","inspectionType":"Plan Review/Pre-Open","establishmentid":"5171","name":"La Noria Bistro","violationCode":"6-101.11","violationDescription":"Materials for indoor floor, wall, and ceiling surfaces under conditions of normal use shall be:\r\n(1) SMOOTH, durable, and EASILY CLEANABLE for areas where FOOD ESTABLISHMENT operations are conducted;\r\n(2) Closely woven and EASILY CLEANABLE carpet for carpeted areas; and\r\n(3) Nonabsorbent for areas subject to moisture such as FOOD preparation areas, walk-in refrigerators, WAREWASHING areas, toilet rooms, mobile FOOD ESTABLISHMENT SERVICING AREAS, and areas subject to flushing or spray cleaning methods.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"wall(s)","subItem":"wall covering(s)","problemDescription":"Not constructed, designed, installed to be","subProblem":"Easily cleanable","location":"PIZZA PREP AREA","subLocation":"At the Wall(s)","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Repair/replace to be smooth and easily cleanable."},{"inspectionid":"41374","inspectionDate":"2/2/2018","inspectionType":"Plan Review/Pre-Open","establishmentid":"5171","name":"La Noria Bistro","violationCode":"5-205.15","violationDescription":"A PLUMBING SYSTEM shall be:\r\n(A) Repaired according to LAW; (P) and\r\n(B) Maintained in good repair.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Plumbing system","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not maintained","subProblem":"","location":"BAR","subLocation":"At the Three compartment sink","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Maintain in good repair"},{"inspectionid":"41374","inspectionDate":"2/2/2018","inspectionType":"Plan Review/Pre-Open","establishmentid":"5171","name":"La Noria Bistro","violationCode":"6-201.11","violationDescription":"Except otherwise approved, and except for antislip floor coverings or applications may be used for safety reasons, floors, floor coverings, walls, wall coverings, and ceilings shall be designed, constructed, and installed so they are SMOOTH and EASILY CLEANABLE.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"wall(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not constructed, designed, installed to be","subProblem":"Easily cleanable","location":"FLOOR AND WALLS","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Repair/replace to be smooth and easily cleanable."},{"inspectionid":"41374","inspectionDate":"2/2/2018","inspectionType":"Plan Review/Pre-Open","establishmentid":"5171","name":"La Noria Bistro","violationCode":"3-603.11","violationDescription":"If an animal FOOD such as  beef, EGGS, FISH, lamb, milk, pork, POULTRY, or shellfish is served or sold raw, undercooked, or without otherwise being processed to eliminate pathogens, either in a READY-TO-EAT form or as an ingredient in another READY-TO-EAT FOOD, the PERMIT HOLDER shall inform CONSUMERS of the significantly increased RISK of consuming such FOODS, by using menu advisories, brochures, lable statements, table tents, placards, or other effective written means. (Pf)\r\nFOOD LAW SEC 6149\r\n...The food establishment may provide the following statement on selection information so that it is made pulblicly available: \"Ask your server about menu items that are cooked to order or served raw.  Consuming raw or undercooked, meats, poultry, shellfish, or eggs may increase your risk of foodborne illness.\"\r\nThe statements must be in a minimum of 11 point font and in a color that provides a clear contrast to background.\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Menu advisories","subItem":"for raw or undercooked food(s)/ingredient(s)","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"MENU(S)","subLocation":"At the Consumer Advisory","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide as required"},{"inspectionid":"41374","inspectionDate":"2/2/2018","inspectionType":"Plan Review/Pre-Open","establishmentid":"5171","name":"La Noria Bistro","violationCode":"4-501.114","violationDescription":"A chemical SANITIZER used in a SANITIZING solution for a manual or\r\nmechanical operation shall meet these limits or as otherwise approved: (P)\r\n\tChlorine        ppm           pH<10             pH<8\r\n\t\t      25              120 F              120 F\r\n\t\t      50              100 F              75 F\r\n\t\t     100              55 F               55 F\r\n                 Iodine           a concentration of between 12.5 and 25 ppm and minimum temp of 75 F and pH of 5 or less or meets manufacturer's specifications. (P)\r\n\r\n                Quats            minimum temperature of 75 F, hardness of 500 ppm or less and meet manufacturers use directions. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Chlorine solution concentration","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Below 25 ppm","subProblem":"","location":"DISH MACHINE","subLocation":"At the Sanitizer","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide correct concentration as stated above.e"},{"inspectionid":"41374","inspectionDate":"2/2/2018","inspectionType":"Plan Review/Pre-Open","establishmentid":"5171","name":"La Noria Bistro","violationCode":"6-301.14","violationDescription":"A sign or poster that notifies FOOD EMPLOYEES to wash their hands shall be provided at all HANDWASHING SINKS used by FOOD EMPLOYEES and shall be clearly visible to FOOD EMPLOYEES.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Handwashing signage","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"At hand sink","location":"HANDSINK(S)","subLocation":"At the Hand washing signage","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide"}]}]}]}},"pageContext":{"eid":"5171"}}